

PROFILE

Highly skilled and resultsoriented professional with
solid academic Inquisitive,
energetic computer science
specialist skilled in
leadership, with a strong
foundation in math, logic, and
cross-platform coding.
Seeking to leverage solid
skills in collaboration,
communication, and
development as a
programmer for Google.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+919664003961

WEBSITE:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vikas-sharma005

EMAIL:

vikas.sharma005@protonmail.com

HOBBIES

- Writing Poetry
- Listening Music
- Football
- Basketball

CERTIFICATION

- Ethical Hacking & Penetration Testing
- Advanced Cardio Life Support
- Mobile App Development
- Email Marketing Basics

VIKAS SHARMA

Andriod|iOS Developer

SUMMARY

FINDING CREATIVE SOLUTIONS TO PROBLEMS IS SOMETHING I HAVE ALWAYS ENJOYED. AS A KID I LOVED TINKERING WITH THINGS THAT WERE BROKEN, FIGURING OUT HOW THEY WORKED, AND FIXING THEM AGAIN. WHEN I FINISHED HIGH SCHOOL, I KNEW EXACTLY HOW I WANTED MY CAREER TO BE.

I AM PURSUING MY BACHELORE'S DEGREE AT POORNIMA INSTITUTE OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY, WHERE I AM LEARNING ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE AND DATA SCIENCE & HOW TO APPLY CRITICAL THINKING AND PROBLEM-SOLVING STRATEGIES TO TODAY'S COMPLEX PROBLEMS.

IM A GOOD LEARNER, HARD WORKING AND SELF MOTIVATED PERSON AND I ALWAYS LIKE TO HELP OTHERS WHATEVER I CAN, BECAUSE I BELIEVE IN "DO GOOD, GET GOOD" POLICY.

EDUCATION

B.Tech in Artificial Intelligence and Data Science *Poornima Institute of Engineering and Technology, Jaipur (Raj.)*November 2021 - Present

Diploma in Ethical Hacking

Alison School August 2021 – April 2022 9.4 GPA

12th in PCM

Tagore International School, Jaipur (Raj.) August 2020 – August 2021 8.8 GPA

10th

National Academy, Alwar (Raj.) March 2018 – August 2019 7.7 GPA

- ICU Nursing
- Advanced Goggle Analytics
- Google Analytics for Power Users
- SAR Data Processing
- Android Kotlin Fundamentals
- ISEA Cyber Hygiene Practitioner

WORK EXPERIENCE

Co-Founder Pie Star Interactive Studios

January 2022 - Present

Pie Star Interactive studios is an newly emerged app and game development start-up where we aim to develop application which can ease people's work and games which rely on new generation technology and graphics. Where myrole is to:

- Providing oversight in management consulting services for organizational leadership, business and operations strategic planning, financial planning, human resource management, contract management, and process improvement resources and tools for trending "performance excellence and operational excellence."
- 2. Executing world-wide human resource strategy in support of the overall business plan and company strategy in a turn around a mature public company.
- 3. Responsible for influencing and developing talent plans and creating a culture to attract, develop, and retain world-class talent while differentiating exceptional performance and highlighting leapfrog as a best-in-class company.

Co-Founder ATIHSKA

August 2022 - Present

ATIHSKA is a newly emerged home security and automation startup where we aim to develop application and an embedded system which can ease people with their home security which rely on new generation technology. Where myrole is to:

- Providing oversight in management consulting services for organizational leadership, business and operations strategic planning, financial planning, human resource management, contract management, and process improvement resources and tools for trending "performance excellence and operational excellence."
- 2. Executing world-wide human resource strategy in support of the overall business plan and company strategy in a turn around a mature public company.
- Responsible for influencing and developing talent plans and creating a culture to attract, develop, and retain world-class talent while differentiating exceptional performance and highlighting leapfrog as a best-in-class company.

Researcher ORBITX INDIA AEROSPACE (p) LTD

June 2022 - Present

The role of a researcher is to use the scientific method and research process to better understand the world around us. Researchers typically work for academic institutions or Space. Researchers gather data during the project life cycle, analyze the data, and publish the findings to aid new research, enrich scholarly literature, and improve decision-making.

Campus Ambassador YHills

March 2022 - April 2022

The main role of Campus Ambassador is to promote the brand of that organization and develop the environment positive towards that particular brand. The responsibility of the campus ambassador to introduce the event and circulate any message that the company wants within the campus.

Following are the benefits of being a campus ambassador:-

- 1. A great leadership opportunity.
- 2. Build public relations/customer service skills.
- 3. Great resume builder.
- 4. Promote the College and your program.
- 5. Meet different college students.
- 6. Chance of building your network.

Robotics Intern Space

February 2022 - March 2022

RESEARCH

Automatic Door Opening System with Face Mask Detection ICSIS-2022

May 2022

Presented a research paper in International Conference on Smart Innovation for Society with title "Automatic Door Opening System with Face Mask Detection".

Comparative Analysis of Different Online teaching Learning Platforms ICSIS-2022

May 2022

Presented a research paper in International Conference on Smart Innovation for Society with title "Comparative Analysis of Different Online teaching Learning Platforms".

Penetration Testing Python Communication Leadership Problem Solving SKILLS 55% 95% 95% 95%